哈佛知识问答  抢答环节
Harvard trivia, the lightning round.
开始
Go.
-普利策奖个数  -四十六
-Pulitzer Prizes. - 46.
-诺贝尔和平奖  -五个
- Nobel peace prizes. - Five.
哈佛图书馆历史最悠久的藏书
What is the oldest book in the Harvard library collection?
-圣经  -错
- The bible. - Wrong.
应该是古腾堡圣经
The gutenberg bible.
谁都知道是古腾堡圣经
Everyone knows it's the gutenberg bible.
是啊 可你没说清楚
Yes, but you didn't say it.
规则要求准确作答
The rules dictate you must be precise,
正如严谨的法律
as the law is a very precise endeavor.
-多少位美国总统...  -八位
- How many U.S. Pr-- - Eight.
犯规  问题还没问完呢
That's not fair, you didn't even finish the question.
但是还是答对了  问题就是
And yet it's right. The question was gonna be
多少位美国总统上过哈佛
"How many U.S. Presidents attended Harvard?"
要我说名字吗
You want names?
不用了  大家都清楚
No, we get it.
最后一轮  罗斯领先一分
Final round. Ross ahead by one.
一人一题  分值加倍
One question each. Points are double.
加分是因为他不想你出局  赛斯
Double 'cause he wants to keep you in the game, Seth.
放马过来吧  罗斯  我可不怕
Bring it on, Ross. I bleed crimson.
这挑衅玩笑  真有爱  我喜欢
Oh, venomous banter. This is adorable, I love it.
罗斯  方形披萨  都在哪买的
Ross, square pizza. Where do you get it?
不是吧
Are you kidding?
每个自爱的哈佛毕业生都知道答案吧
Any self-respecting Harvard alumnus would know the answer to that.
熬夜学习想吃方披萨
Late night studying and you want square pizza,
去哪买呢
where do you go?
我比较喜欢吃汉堡
You know, I'm more of a burger guy.
摄入足够蛋白质学得更好
I study better on protein.
太可惜了
I mean, that's just... pathetic.
答案是匹诺曹店
It's Pinocchio's.
我答对我的题就会赢
Mm, I answer mine, I win.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
现任美国最高法庭法官中
How many current U.S. Supreme Court justices
有几位法官上过哈佛
are from our alma mater?
五位
Five.
看到了吧  我说过凯勒要更胜一筹
Hah! See, I told you Keller was better.
欠我二十美元
You owe me 20.
-真了不起  -有啥想说的没  罗斯
- Awesome. - Got anything to say, Ross?
没有  只是你的回答是错的
Nope. Just that the answer's wrong.
斯卡利亚  罗伯茨
Scalia, Roberts,
肯尼迪  布雷耶  卡根
Kennedy, Breyer, Kagan.
金斯伯根
Ginsberg.
鲁斯・贝德・金斯伯根读的是哥伦比亚
Ruth Bader Ginsberg went to Columbia.
她毕业于哥伦比亚
She graduated from Columbia,
但她之前还在哈佛读过两年
after she attended Harvard for two years.
问题问的是
The question was phrased
"有几位法官上过哈佛"
"How many justices were from harvard?"
她上过哈佛法学院的期刊
Well, she was on the Harvard Law Review.
她转至哥伦比亚就读时
And when she arrived at Columbia as a transfer,
是哈佛在校生的身份
she was from Harvard.
规则要求准确作答
The rules dictate that you must be precise,
正如严谨的法律
as the law is a precise endeavor.
告诉过你罗斯是大热
Told you Ross was hot.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
这是第二名的奖品
This is what you get for second place.
大奖属于胜利者
To the victor belongs the spoils.
一个案子  无偿代理  你全权负责
A case. Pro bono, one of your very own.
恭喜  好好享用吧
Congratulations, enjoy.
路易知道了
Louis knows.
-路易知道什么  -我见不得人的小秘密
- Louis knows what? - My dirty little secret.
-你是加拿大人吗  -哈哈哈哈
- You're Canadian? - Ha, ha, ha, ha.
不是  他知道我不是哈佛毕业的
No, he knows that I didn't go to harvard.
他不知道
No, he doesn't.
你为什么这么肯定
How can you be so sure about that?
因为你现在还跟我走在一起
Because you're walking with me right now.
他举办了这场哈佛知识问答
He did this whole harvard trivia thing,
又问到那个披萨
and then he brought up this pizza--
这也不能说明他知道
Doesn't mean he knows.
我觉着我们需要
Look, I think we need to hack
入侵哈佛系统
into Harvard's system or something.
把我的信息输入进去
You know, put my records in.
我不行  周末有约了
I can't, I'm booked this weekend.
我要闯进诺克斯堡[军事重地]
I'm breaking into fort knox.
还几个偷的多布隆金币
I gotta return some stolen doubloons.
太有喜感了  我是认真的
Okay, hilarious. I'm serious.
只要你不惹祸
Listen, nobody's gonna check into your past
没人会翻你的老底
unless you give them reason to.
路易是不光明磊落  但他没那么大胆
Louis is devious, but he's not bold.
他想不到我们会这么做
He won't think we did this.
因为他自己不会做这种事
Because he'd never think to do it himself.
多布隆金币吗
Doubloons?
你那荒谬的建议
The ridiculousness of your suggestion
害我说了个这么傻的词
warranted the use of a silly word.
明白
Got it.
刚刚走的是奎汀・桑兹吧
Was that Quentin Sainz I just saw leaving?
你认识他吗
Mm-hmm. You know him?
听说过
I know of him.
他为什么跟你握手  还吻你的手
Why was he holding your hands? Kissing them?
你想说什么  哈维
What are you implying, Hharvey?
不知道  也许你俩确定关系了
I don't know, maybe you two are going steady.
我是说  看起来像是
I was implying that it looked like
你接他的案子  他感激涕零
he was grateful to you for taking his case.
很好  事实也是如此
Good, 'cause that's exactly what it was.
这步棋不妥  赢了也许能大赚一笔
That's a bad move. We may make money
但是一旦输了...
billing out on their defense, but when we lose--
输的可能性很大  长远利益会受损
Which we will--it's gonna hurt us in the long run.
-你怎么知道我们会输  -职业直觉
- How do you know we'll lose? - Because it's my job to know.
他公司治疗肌萎缩性侧索硬化的灵药
And his company's A.L.S. Wonder drug
吃死人了
is killing people.
肌萎缩性侧索硬化是不治之症
A.L.S. is incurable.
吃那药的人本来终究也会死的
And everyone who is taking that drug is going to die anyway.
这就是你的辩护词吗
Hm. That's your defense?
加速病人的死亡  变成服务公众了吗
If he kills them a little faster, it's a public service?
我们的抗辩是指控不实
Our defense is those allegations are untrue.
他把这事传得沸沸扬扬的
He has taken this story all over town,
没有律所会接这个案子
and not a single firm thinks he has a case.
所以他来找我
Which is why he came to me.
他需要有人信任他
Because he wants someone who believes in him.
你为什么要相信他
And what is it exactly that makes you believe in him?
我们结婚那段日子
Well, I got to know his character pretty well
足以让我深知他的品行
during the time that we were married.
奎汀明天会来见你
Quentin is expecting you tomorrow.
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：圆圆  猴子  马蒂  米苏  Lyra
时间轴：小怡子 潘叔  校对：vero  后期：飞飞  总监：丢丢
■
诉 讼 双 雄
第一季 第四集
-你昨晚忘带这个了  -我没忘
- You forgot this last night. - I didn't forget that.
我没打算接这个案子
I have no intention of taking this case.
但是我给你准备了这个
Though, I did get you this.
-什么  -结婚礼物
- What is it? - A wedding gift.
不好意思送晚了
I'm sorry it's so late,
但是由于我都不知道你结婚了
but it's hard to be on time
想及时送礼  也很有难度
when I never knew you were married.
你在跟谁约会吗  哈维
Are you seeing anyone, Harvey?
你不想告诉我  我也不在意
You don't wanna tell me, and I don't really care.
因为你我都是
Because you and I share the same trait
注重保护隐私的人
of keeping our personal lives personal.
你结过婚了
You were married.
那还是你读哈佛时候的事  感情进展不顺
It happened when you were at Harvard, didn't work out.
我们都太专注于自己的事业了
We were too dedicated to our careers,
我想说的也就这些了
And that's all I'm going to say about it.
好吧  你是对的
Okay. You're right.
不关我事
It's none of my business.
-这个案子我还是不接  -为什么
- I'm still not taking this case. - Why is that?
因为有时候我会做出让客户不爽的事情
Because sometimes I do things that my clients don't like.
如果他们的前妻监视着我
And if their ex-wives are looking over my shoulders,
倒也没啥事
that's not really a problem.
但是如果他们的前妻是我的经营合伙人
But when their ex-wives are also my managing partner,
我就放不开手脚了
that hamstrings me.
如果想让我扳回官司
And if I'm gonna turn this loser into a winner,
我就不能被束缚  绝对不能
I can't be hamstrung. I can't have that.
你想怎么做都行
Do what you gotta do.
-你不会干预吗  -我刚才不是说了嘛
- You won't interfere? - What did I just say?
如果不是辉瑞  阿目金
Do you have any idea how hard it is
或者默克这类大制药公司
to develop a new drug
你知道普通公司要开发新药有多难吗
if you're not Pfizer, or Amgen, or Merck?
这事很重要  哈维
This is important, Harvey.
如果奎汀是来找一个信任他的人
If Quentin came to you looking for someone to trust him,
你为什么不接他的案子
why aren't you handling this case yourself?
与你无关
That's none of your concern.
我不是以同事的身份问你
Well, I'm not asking you that as your colleague,
而是以奎汀的律师身份问你
I'm asking you as Quentin's attorney.
我和奎汀分居以后
After Quentin and I separated,
他开始和一个研究顾问约会
he started seeing one of his research consultants.
她叫丽萨  他们现在还在一起
Lisa. They're still together.
但是他没娶她
But he never married her.
她不希望我插手这个案子
She doesn't want me on the case.
好极了
Oh, terrific.
你硬塞给我一个必输的案子
You're sticking me with a losing case,
还塞给我一个既不喜欢你
and a girlfriend who isn't gonna like me
也不会喜欢我的女朋友
anymore than she likes you.
我敢肯定这不是第一次
Well, I'm sure it's not the first time
有人不喜欢你了  哈维
someone hasn't liked you, Harvey.
谁不喜欢我了
Who doesn't like me?
他就像一个无恶不作的魔鬼
Picture the devil without the charm.
好吧  所以说这两年来楼主都是卡里斯基
Okay, so Karinski owned this building for two years?
没错  随后情况就急转直下了
Yeah, then things got bad.
零下三度时供热断了  差点把我冻死
Three below, the heat went out and I nearly froze to death.
炉子又发生了煤气泄漏
Then a gas leak in my stove.
都能闻到那股味  可他却说没事
You could smell the damn thing, but he said it was fine.
我打了一个月的电话  最后还是自己换的
I called for a month, then I had to replace it myself.
为什么不干脆搬走
Why didn't you just move?
我是在这所公寓里长大的
This is the apartment that I grew up in.
这里是我唯一熟悉的地方
It's the only place I've ever known.
我没有兄弟姐妹
I don't have any brothers or sisters.
我的父母  也不在了
My parents... not with me anymore.
我不会离开我和他们仅有的维系之所
I'm not leaving the one connection I have to them.
你说你睡不着觉  是压力大还是
You said you weren't sleeping. Are you stressed out, or--?
-有臭虫  -不会吧
- Bedbugs. - No.
我的房间简直爬满了臭虫
My place is literally crawling with them.
想到自己一关灯  他们就会爬过来
Could you sleep knowing the minute you turn out the light,
-你还能睡着吗  -睡不着
- they're coming for you? - No, I couldn't.
拿不出证据  卡里斯基就不管
Well, Karinski won't do anything about it without proof,
可我找不来有关部门去证实
And I can't get someone from the city down
那里有臭虫
to verify they're there.
别担心  我可以
Don't worry. I can.
要等两周  下周四
Two weeks. Next Thursday.
我想你没听清我说什么
I-I-I-I don't think that you heard me.
我现在就要人过去
I need someone down there today.
-要等两周  下周四  -好了
- Two weeks, next thursday. - Okay.
我想跟你们的主管谈谈
Uh, I'd like to speak to your supervisor, please.
你可以下周三来
You can do that next Wednesday.
好吧  格兰达  我告诉你从现在起
Okay, Glenda, let me tell you what I'm gonna do
到下周三  我会怎么做
between now and next wednesday...
我很清楚你要怎么做
I know exactly what you're gonna do.
每个律师都会这么威胁我
You're gonna do what every lawyer threatens to do.
你会递交409/3投诉
You're gonna file a 409/3 grievance
说我没有格尽职守
Claiming that I did not fulfill my obligation
让你马上见到我的主管
to promptly direct you to my supervisor.
这份投诉将会在下周三递交给我的主管
A grievance that will be passed on to my supervisor next Wednesday.
不  我要做的是  雇一名私家侦探
No, what I'm gonna do is hire a private investigator
调查从你出生到下周二期间
to look into every aspect of your life
你生活的方方面面
from the day you were born until next Tuesday.
有任何发现  我都会加以利用
And then I'm gonna use whatever it is they find
让你整天祈祷  能保住这份
to make you wish that your biggest problem
你看来也厌恶十足的工作
was keeping this job that you seem to hate so much.
没错  我是个与众不同的律师  格兰达
Yeah, I'm not like every other lawyer, Glenda.
你刚才说你叫什么
What did you say your name was?
斯佩克特
Specter.
哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
-你是棒球迷吗  -是啊
- You're a baseball fan? - Oh, yeah.
那你应该知道卢・格里格是个狠角色
Then I assume you know Lou Gehrig was a bad man.
不然也不会被人称作火车了
They didn't call him the iron horse for nothing.
后来他得了肌萎缩侧索硬化症
Then he got A.L.S.
知道他怎样了吗
You know what it did to him?
他的手瘫痪了  之后是脚
His hands locked up, then his legs,
接着失语  最后窒息
His speech, eventually his breathing.
无法控制
Couldn't control 'em.
他的头脑很清楚  可是身体却
His mind knew what it wanted, but his body--
他完全被困住了  无法自理
He was trapped inside, unable to do anything.
就算今时今日  患上肌萎缩侧索硬化症
Even today, you get A.L.S.,
不出三五年也必死无疑
within three to five years, you die.
如果吃了你的药出现肝衰竭  会死得更快
Or sooner, if someone takes your drug and their liver fails.
我们的药能减轻最后几年的痛苦
Our drug makes people's remaining years better,
还能让他们的预期寿命翻倍
And it doubles their life expectancy.
除了那些出现肝脏衰竭的人
Except for the people who's livers are failing.
-你不...  -丽萨
- You don't - Lisa.
不要紧
It's okay.
我知道杰西卡为什么喜欢你了
I can see why Jessica likes you.
你说话直来直往
You cut through the bullshit.
我就喜欢她这点
That's something I always loved about her.
只是她这么说话的魅力  会比我少一点
She just does it with a little less charm than I do.
她是不是比你高一点
Isn't she a little taller than you?
-她穿高跟鞋了  -我来告诉你
- It's the heels. - Let me tell you
一种药物通过审批都需要什么
what it takes to get a drug approved today.
药物上架之前  我们投入了
We were $139 million into development
一亿三千九百万用于研发
before we ever hit the shelves.
所有的要求我们都一一通过了
We jumped through every hoop they threw at us,
花了八年时间证明我们的药是安全的
And we proved our drug was safe for eight years.
所以你说这些控告是毫无根据的
So you're saying these claims are baseless?
在这六个晚期病人身上
We're talking about six terminal patients
存在一系列的医疗问题
with a wide array of medical issues.
凭什么说是我们公司的药物导致的
And they're saying my company's drug caused this?
莱昂纳多・迪卡普里奥落水的原因
They were drinking coffee on the Titanic.
也不会是当时人们都在泰坦尼克号上喝咖啡吧
I don't think that put Leonardo Dicaprio in the water.
既然杰西卡向我担保了
Since Jessica vouched for you,
我就会相信你说的话
I'm gonna go ahead and believe what you're telling me.
但鉴于其他药品公司已决定要让你曝光
But since these other firms determined you have exposure,
我们就得这么办  赔他们钱
Here's what we're gonna do. We're gonna pay them.
赔他们一点点钱
We're gonna pay them a little bit of money
你就可以继续救死扶伤
So you can keep saving lives,
因为如果这事拖久了
because if we drag this out,
人们就不会相信你的药能救命了
people won't think of your drug as a way to save lives,
他们会觉得你的药能致命
They'll think of it as a death sentence.
房屋管理处的人
The guy from the housing department's
五分钟之后就到
gonna be here in about five minutes.
你是怎么办到的
How did you manage that?
如果把情况跟他们说清楚
You know, they're actually pretty receptive
他们还是会听进去的
when you explain the situation to them.
为了防止虫害蔓延  只能这么做
That's what you have to do to prevent the spread.
我都忍痛扔了很多东西了
I had to get rid of most of my things--
衣服  收藏的唱片  书
Clothes, record collection, books.
我当初还有第一版的《麦田守望者》呢
I had a first edition "Catcher in the Rye",
-你知道有多值钱吗  -不知道
- You know what that was worth? - No.
那些虫子能潜伏十八个月
The bugs can live dormant for 18 months.
你得把所有东西都扔了
You just have to throw everything out.
-弗兰克  -卡里斯基
- Frank! - Karinski.
-你在这啊  -是啊
- You're here. - yes.
-我住这  -你还有脸说
- I live here. - Funny you should mention that,
你都四个月没交房租了
'cause you haven't paid rent in four months,
-我真不确定了  -我没交房租
- So I wasn't sure. - I haven't paid rent
是因为你没有...
because you haven't--
弗兰克不交房租
Frank has withheld rent
是因为这公寓住不了人
because the apartment is not habitable.
纽约住房规定  副二章  第四条
New York housing code, sub-chapter two, article four
-第27至20节  -不交房租就走人
- Section 27-20-- - Hey, no rent, no apartment.
这是我的规矩
That's my code.
你想依法办事是吧
But if you want something legal...
这是法院的命令  三天之内给我滚出去
There's a court order. You got three days to get out.
不然治安部的人也会来替你搬家的
Or the sheriff's department will empty the place for you.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
你迟到了
You're late.
是因为路易的无偿案件  我
Look, it was Louis' pro bono, I--
这是我的西装  我办公室那套备用的
Hey, that's my suit. My extra suit from my office.
是的  都怪路易  那个当事人的房间
Yeah, it's Louis' fault. I went to the client's place,
到处都是臭虫  所以当我回到办公室
It was overrun with bedbugs, so I went back to the office--
你把臭虫带到我的办公室了
You tracked bedbugs into my office?
-没有  -那你裸体进去的
- No. - You walked in there naked?
不是  是唐娜给我送到楼下男厕的
No, Donna met me in the downstairs men's room...
够了  唐娜被解雇了  你得给我买套新的
Okay, Donna's fired, and you're buying me an extra suit.
还有  这是三件套的
By the way, that's a three-piece suit.
马甲呢
Where's the vest?
没错  我正想跟你说这事呢
Yeah, I've been meaning to talk to you about that.
马甲  还要穿马甲吗
Vests? Really?
戴着自行车头盔的人懂什么
Says the guy with the bike helmet.
安全第一嘛
Uh, safety first.
慢点
Come on.
这就是生产艾米林克斯药的大楼啊
Ah, the house that Amylinx built.
不错  真不错
Nice. Very nice.
我叫科林・ 彻奇  桑兹先生
Collin Church, Mr. Sainz
还有斯佩克特先生
and Mr. Specter,
您姗姗来迟  为解决我们这小小的法律纠纷
lately arrived to our little legal dispute.
法律纠纷吗  我看是勒索
You say legal dispute, I say shakedown.
这二者的差别总是很微妙  不是吗
Always a fine line between the two, n'est pas?
说实话  如果我们坐在这
Look, we can sit here and posture
讨论各自在案件中的优势和劣势
about the strengths and weaknesses of our cases,
那对我来说真是无聊透顶了
but frankly, that's gonna bore the hell out of me.
真的吗
Seriously?
-还可以更少的  -我说会更多
- It could be much lower. - It could be much higher.
那就当它正好吧
Then let's pretend it's just right.
我的委托人寿命缩短了
My client's lives are being cut short.
而且根据公式计算
And according to accepted calculations,
现在一条命可值790万
the current value of a life is $7.9 million.
你这连零头都不够
You're not even offering pennies on that.
那些公式是环保局
Those happen to be E.P.A. Calculations
根据完整的平均寿命计算的
based on a full life expectancy.
考虑到原告的寿命
Adjusted for plaintiffs
本来就时日不多了
Who's expectancy is just a fragment of this,
也就只值143427美元
yields a value of $143,427.
估算值
Approximately.
你们这位小朋友没明白
What your child fails to understand is that
对于一个只剩下三至五年寿命的人
For someone with only three to five years to live,
每一天都是无比珍贵的
Each day is worth infinitely more.
关键在于惩罚性损害赔偿的问题
But the real crux is the punitive damages.
如果你的当事人想让我相信
Because if your client wants to sell me the idea
这些年来他对药的副作用一无所知
that he didn't know about these side effects years ago.
我是不会相信的
I'm not buying it.
所以我们要求赔偿2.5亿
Which is why we want $250 million.
-什么  -奎汀
- What? - Quentin.
不可能  这太不讲道理了
No, man. This is outrageous.
你知道自己在干嘛吗
Do you know what you're doing?
你是在让我的公司破产
You're bankrupting this company
还缩短了那些服用我公司药物的人们
and taking away years of life from real people
得以轻松行走  交谈
who are walking, talking, and breathing easier
和呼吸的年限
because of the drug we make.
我并不代表这些人
I don't represent those people.
我的当事人...
My clients--
要求巨额索赔的可能性极低
Have tenuous claims at best.
除非你们六个人中有
And unless one of your six is
鲁伯特・默多克[新闻集团总裁]
Rupert Murdoch.
不然你想都别想
You're out of your mind.
好吧
Okay.
紧急警告  桑兹药厂艾米林克斯药物服用者
-你登报了  -还没  但我会的
- You printed that? - Well, not yet. But I will.
你知道这算诽谤吧
You realize that's libelous.
也许是  也许不是
Maybe it is, maybe it isn't.
不过一旦刊登出来后  你我都清楚
But after it runs, you and I both know,
诽不诽谤就不重要了
It won't much matter.
没什么好说的了  我不接受勒索
We're done here. I don't take to extortion.
无论西装有多赞  我也不会
I'm not gonna be bullied by an ambulance-chaser
被专接事故案的无名小卒恐吓
no matter how nice his suit.
这西服确实很赞  不是吗
It is nice, isn't it?
意大利制造  相当合身
Italian. And it fits.
两亿五  桑兹先生
$250 million, Mr. Sainz.
我给你们四天时间
I'll give you four days.
彻奇想玩下去  我们就奉陪到底
Church wants to play, we play.
我早上还有个房屋案子要开庭
I have housing court in the morning.
只是个房屋案件  你奶奶都能打赢
It's housing court. Your grandmother could win.
我们先查一下他当事人的
Let's see just how real
肝脏到底出了什么问题
his clients' liver problems are.
如果事情属实  我们就说那是由于
Are if they are real, we suggest they're from
疾病本身  或用药不慎
the disease itself, or they took the wrong dose,
或者他们在鸡尾酒里加了混合药物
or they took a cocktail of combined drugs.
还有  我要看一下奎汀公司的财务状况
Also, I wanna see Quentin's company financials.
我已经跟他们说过了
I already asked for them once.
打个电话给他们  随时跟进
I want you to call them and follow-up.
我要知道彻奇可能查到的任何资料
I wanna know everything church could go after.
我们不在这儿想谈和方案
So we've gone from settlement
而要采取极端措施了
to scorched earth.
我不想开一张两亿五的支票给他
I didn't feel like writing a $1/4 billion check.
-现在还只是谈判而已  -没错
- It's a negotiation. - Exactly.
所以我才要为下一轮充分武装
That's why I'm arming myself for the next round.
靠查奎汀的老底吗
By digging into Quentin?
我可是童子军
I'm a boy scout.
我不打无准备之仗
I like to be prepared.
你是说你会像童子军那样
So you think you'll look like a boy scout
让那些奄奄一息的病人出庭作证
By putting dying people on the stand
再让他们败诉
and tearing them apart?
那你就是个混蛋
You're gonna look like an asshole.
虽然他们每个人都声称有副作用
For every one they claim has a side effect,
但我们这儿有600人没发现副作用
We have 600 who don't.
如果让别人以为我是混蛋
And if I need to look like an asshole
就能向陪审团说明
to convince the jury
几百个人的命远重于一个人的命
that hundreds are more important than the one,
我也不用担心的睡不着了
I'm not gonna lose a minute's sleep over it.
我明早还有个房屋案件要开庭
Well, I have court in the morning.
我不明白
Oh, I'm-- I'm not clear.
我是在和我的经营合伙人说话
Was this a conversation with my managing partner
还是在和我客户的前妻说话
or my client's ex-wife?
你得妥善处理这件案子  哈维
You need to settle this case, Harvey.
我会的  只要你不插手
Which I will do if you stay out of it...
就像你之前保证的
As you promised.
好好处理
Make it go away.
-瑞秋  -走开
- Rachel. - Go away.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
谁又找你茬了  迈克
Who's picking on you now, Mikey?
老爸老妈吵架咯
Mom and Dad are fighting.
-哈维和杰西卡  -你担心个什么劲啊
-Harvey and Jessica. - What do you care?
我只是有点担心
Oh, I'm just rattled.
明天是我第一次出庭  房屋案件
My first trial tomorrow in housing court.
房屋的案子吗
Housing court?
我都能打赢这官司  你能行的
I could win at housing court. You'll be fine.
但要是穿这件衬衫就另当别论了
But not if you wear that suit.
卡维罗与卡里斯基房租纠纷诉讼案
Carvello versus Karinski properties.
通常这类案件是怎么审的
So how does this usually work?
通常在审讯开始
Well, usually the trial starts,
法官会坐在那  然后
and there's the judge, and then...you know,
大家就开始辩护
people say things.
你以前从来没接过案子吧
You've never done this before, have you?
第一次开车之前
Well, I never drove a car before
我也没开过车啊
the first time I drove one,
但是我现在不是也安然无恙吗
and I'm still here, aren't I?
这是你第一次上庭吗
This is your first time?
我是你的第一个对手
I'm your first?
别担心  我保证不会手下留情的
Don't worry, I promise not to be gentle.
弗兰克  见到你真高兴
Frank. It's nice to see you.
最后一次了
One last time.
请允许我...
If it pleases the court--
请允许我宣布何人何时开始陈词
It pleases the court to decide who speaks and when.
我还是坐下吧
I'll sit down.
今天的案子是关于四千元的房租拖欠
We're talking about $4,000 in withheld rent pas--
是的  法官大人  但是我们有
Yes, your honor. But we have receipts
维修  失窃衣物的收据  还有...
for repairs, lost clothing, as well as...
四千元  没错  法官大人
$4,000. Yes, your honor.
她是在和我说话
She was talking to me.
他为什么没付房租  对方律师
Why hasn't he paid, counselor?
法官是在问你呢
That one was for you.
是因为臭虫  法官大人
Bedbugs, your honor.
我掌握的收据资料显示
I have receipts that show
我的当事人若要解决这些问题
my client's financial outlay
所需的财力远远超过他的实际收入水平
to rectify the problem far exceeds the amount.
房屋管理部门确认了臭虫的情况属实了吗
Housing department certified the presence of bedbugs?
-是的  法官大人  -房租减免呢
- Uh, yes, your honor. - Abatement?
借过
Excuse me.
我来吧  给
I'll do it. There you go.
法官大人  这是房屋收回听证会
Your honor, this is an eviction hearing.
重点不在于房屋是否适合居住
The pertinent question is not habitability,
而在于对方是否已付房租
but whether or not rent has been paid.
实际上  城市法规明确规定
Actually, city code states that
不能保证房屋的适居度
rent may be withheld
可以不支付房租
if the warranty of habitability is breached.
那样的话  我要求查看第三方对
In that case, we request to see the checks
罗斯先生当事人的担保核对
Mr. Ross' client has placed in escrow.
核对  第三方的...
Checks, in escrow.
房租减免与否取决于此
Pending the outcome of a rent abatement hearing?
法规里可没这么规定
That's not in the code.
这是不成文的规矩
It is the accepted practice.
因此在这个法庭上是适用的
And therefore binding in this courtroom.
我想你的当事人
Your client did
应该出钱进行过第三方担保吧
put money in escrow, I assume.
-我没有多余的钱了啊  -法官大人
- I didn't have any money left-- - Your honor...
赞成收回房屋
Eviction upheld.
但是法官大人  他...
But your honor, he--
看到我敲木槌了吗
Did you see me bang the gavel?
那意味着判决已定  下一个案子
That means step aside. Next case.
你永远不会忘记你的第一次的
You never forget your first.
你知不知道如果一个新棒球投手
You know what happens to pitchers
首场比赛失利会有什么下场吗  迈克
when they get shelled in rookie league, Mike?
你觉得他们还会成为种子选手吗
You think they make it to the bigs?
或许他们会去参军
Or do they just end up
最后惨遭遗忘
on some sad American legion team of has-beens?
我明白  我输了  我很抱歉
I get it, I lost. I'm sorry.
你很抱歉
Well, you're sorry.
-那样的话  -不  我真的很抱歉
- In that case-- - No, I am sorry.
但现在我要帮哈维查些资料
But right now I have some research to do for Harvey,
-所以失陪一下  -还记得你偷走了
- So if you'll excuse me. - Remember when you stole
我让你谈下来的那个客户吗
that client I had you bring in?
那时你真是风光啊  不是吗
That was a good time for you, wasn't it?
我给了你一个无足轻重的案子
See, I gave you a nothing case so that
即使你打赢了
when you did win
那对你的事业也起不了什么作用
it would still do nothing for your career.
但我还是期望你能打赢
But I still expected you to win.
所以  我想
So yeah, I guess...
你还是继续查你的资料吧
Go back to your research.
也许你就只能干这个
Maybe that is your niche.
也许吧
Maybe it is.
大多数清晨  我都不用坐在轮椅上
Most mornings, I can make it out of the chair
可以在地板上走动
and get across the floor.
还能抱起我女儿
And I can hold my daughter.
参与调查的有多少人
How many were in the study?
两年多里  有412人
412, over 2 years.
他们的所有录像资料我们都有
And we have videos of all of them.
25%的人服用的是安慰剂
25% were given placebos.
其余人都服用了不等剂量的艾米林克斯
The rest, varying doses of Amylinx.
超过半数的人  都像这位患者一样
And more than half are like that one,
病情好转地相当快
showing significant signs of improvement.
你的意思是治疗一点都不会损害肝脏
And you're telling me there was nothing affecting the liver?
是的
Yes.
如果你来是为了质问我这个的
If you're just coming to question that,
那可以直接跳过了
we'll move on.
你讨厌奎汀去找他前妻帮忙  对吗
You don't like it that Quentin went to his ex-wife, do you?
没错
No, I don't.
我不想他过去的包袱阻碍他的前途
I don't want any garbage from the past getting in the way.
奎汀在这里做出的成就  堪比奇迹
I mean, what Quentin's done here is nothing short of miraculous.
我想我可能找到了一个挽救奇迹的办法
I think I may have found a way to keep that miracle going.
我在翻看原告的医疗档案
I was going through the plaintiff's medical files,
我发现了这个
and then I found this.
好啊
This is good.
这真太好了
This is really good.
琼斯告诺克一案
Jones versus Norco...
沃什本告霍斯尼股份有限公司一案
Washburn versus Hawthorne Incorporated...
事实上  有七起案件
actually, seven cases that Mr. Church solicited
彻奇先生都是作为原告律师控告制药公司
lawsuits against pharmaceutical companies.
在每起案件中  他都能达成庭外和解
In each case, he was able to exact a settlement
因为这些公司知道  即使他们赢了官司
because the company knew that even if they won,
这样的拉锯战也会造成比和解更大的损失
a protracted battle would do more damage than settling.
你这说法有证据吗
You have evidence of that?
我们案件中的二号原告  埃莉诺・贝克
Plaintiff number two in our case, Eleanor Baker.
她同时还是
She also happens to be
琼斯告诺克一案的七号原告
plaintiff number seven in Jones versus Norco.
他这是回收再利用他的原告  挺环保的
He's recycling plaintiffs. That's very green of you.
彻奇先生你怎么说
Mr. Church?
斯佩克特先生有力证  我这儿也有
Mr. Specter has his documents, I have mine
这些文件显示了  药管局批准药品生产前
showing that prior to FDA approval of his drug,
奎汀・桑兹的公司濒临破产
Quentin Sainz's company was on the verge of bankruptcy.
药品上市后三个月
Three months after that drug hit the market,
销售额冲到一季度3800万美元
sales rocketed to $38 million a quarter,
这显然是伪造临床试验
which is clear financial motive
的财务动机啊
for falsifying clinical trials.
法官大人  这听起来
Now, Your Honor, does that sound like
也不是妄加推断吧
a groundless claim to you?
我让你去查他们的财务状况的
I told you to go over those financials.
我跟他要了五次了  他根本没给我
I asked him five times, he never gave them to me.
-法官大人  -斯佩克特先生
- Your Honor. - Mr. Specter,
你可以在庭审的时候质问他的辩护手法
you can question his tactics all you like at trial,
但他说的对
but he's right.
确实存在欺瞒作弊的财务动机
That right there is financial motive for fraud
本案进入下一阶段
this case is moving forward.
谢谢  法官大人
Thank you, Your Honor.
杰西卡  你来这儿干嘛
Jessica, what're you doing here?
进来
Get in.
我正要去买杯咖啡呢
I was just about to get some coffee.
我听说了你在法庭上受挫的事
Heard about your little setback in court.
因为我的客户隐瞒不报而遭偷袭
Getting blind-sided by my own client holding back
不叫受挫  叫受辱
isn't a setback, it's an embarrassment.
-你说什么呢  -你有没有想过
- What are you talking about? - Did you ever think
现在该认识到  或许他不是你想的那种
it's time to consider that he isn't the upstanding man
正直的人
that you think he is?
我们还是夫妻的时候
When we were married...
当奎汀知道我接的客户是有罪的时候
when I took a client Quentin knew was guilty,
他就唠叨个不停
he never shut up about it.
他会一直说要黑白分明
He went on, and on, about right and wrong.
听上去像个自以为是的讨厌鬼
Sounds annoyingly self-righteous.
确实
It was.
但这也是我知道他不会这么做的原因
But it's also how I know he didn't do this.
不管他犯了什么错  奎汀从没对我撒谎
For all his faults, Quentin has never lied to me before.
他也没对此事撒谎
And he's not lying about this.
所以别再质疑他的人品  想法赢得案子
So stop questioning his ethics and start winning this case.
我们说好你不会插手的
We had a deal that you were gonna stay out of it.
我掌握的情况  你并不都清楚
You don't know everything I know.
-那就给我看看  -这还叫不插手吗
- All right. - That's not staying out of it.
你说得对
No, you're right.
我现在要插手了
I'm not staying out of it anymore.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们查他底细查得这么彻底
You looked into his background this deeply?
调查结果就是调查结果
The investigation reveals what it reveals.
如果他对此撒谎  对别的事也会撒谎
If he lied about this, he could've lied about anything.
你以为我不知道
You think I didn't know
他跟我分手之前就跟丽萨有一腿了吗
He started with Lisa before we were separated?
这我早知道了  哈维  我早不计较了
This is old news, Harvey. I moved on a long time ago.
杰西卡  这是他行为模式
Jessica, it's a pattern of behavior.
奎汀来找我  是因为他知道
Quentin came to me because he knew
我认为他是个好人  我还是这样认为的
I thought he was a good man, and I still do.
你显然不这么认为
You obviously don't.
我要接手这件案子
I'm taking the case.
那丽萨那儿怎么办
What about Lisa?
要是丽萨对此有意见
If Lisa has a problem with it,
让她来找我好了
then Lisa can take it up with me.
挺讽刺的是不是
It's kind of ironic, isn't it?
我们昨天都在法庭上败下阵来
You and I both lost in court yesterday.
你输了  房屋纠纷吗
You lost... in housing court?
你怎么能输掉房屋纠纷呢
How does one lose in housing court?
那种案子不请律师都能赢啊
People win there without lawyers.
对方有律师  叫塔纳卡  她还
Well, he had a lawyer, Tanaka, and she--
-薇薇安・塔纳卡吗  -对  你认识她吗
- Vivien Tanaka? - Yeah, what, you know her?
要是你的房东雇了薇薇安・塔纳卡
If your landlord's using Vivien Tanaka,
那这就不是臭虫的问题了
this isn't about bedbugs.
薇薇安・塔纳卡替曼哈顿一半的大厦打官司
Vivien Tanaka represents half the high-rises in Manhattan.
这不是什么房租纠纷  房东要盖公寓大厦
This isn't a petty rent dispute. Your guy's going condo.
那好啊
Well, that's great.
为了改造  逼迫弗兰克搬家构成骚扰罪
Forcing Frank out for conversion is harassment,
我能用这个告他
I can go after him for that.
不  你想打倒薇薇安
No, you wanna take down Vivien,
你最好多带上几个客户
you better go in there with more than just one client.
指出事件的普遍性  调解费就上去了
You show the pattern, the settlement goes up.
如果他们真对他这么干
If they did this to him,
我敢保证他们还对别人这么干过
I guarantee they've done this to others.
那我应该去找弗兰克楼里的其他人了
So I should find other people in Frank's building?
大胆设想
Think bigger.
怎么个大法
Bigger how?
卡里斯基拥有五栋楼
Karinski owns five buildings
之前都是租金管制公寓
and they all used to be rent-controlled,
为保护低收入者有屋可住实施的房屋管制政策
但现在都是一个单元150万
but now they go for a million and a half a unit.
利润可观啊
Nice profit margin.
我去房屋管理处
I went to look for housing department complaints
找他改造前一年的公寓投诉
in the year prior to his remodel.
每一栋楼里  掏不起改造后房租的住户
In each one of them, tenants who couldn't buy into the conversion
后来都对垃圾  采暖或臭气提起过投诉
ended up with some complaint-- garbage, heat, air.
所有人  一个一个的都被卡里斯基赶出去了
All of them, one by one, Karinski drove them out.
你在投诉上查不到他们的名字吗
You couldn't get their names from housing complaints?
查到了  我拿到一些名字
No, it gave me some names.
但我需要让此事看起来比他的大楼更严重
But I need to make this bigger than just his building.
我只有一小时午休时间
Look, I only get one hour off a day for lunch,
现在还没休上呢  你真需要我帮你吗
and I never take it. Do you really need me for this?
看见这对离开大厦的人了吗
See these people who are leaving the building?
整栋楼都是这样的人
The entire building looks like them.
我知道我还算干净利落  但是
I know I clean up okay, but...
你要我让你提升点档次
Mm, you need me to class you up a bit.
-不是档次的事  -就是档次的事
- Not class, but-- - Class.
好吧  只有能进门就行
All right, whatever gets you through the door.
-走吧  准备好了吗  -好了
- Come on, are you ready? - Yeah.
你好  我夫人和我
Hi, there. My wife and I
想来看看一些新单元
are here to see some of the new units.
是不是啊  亲爱的
Isn't that right, honey?
你觉得怎么样啊  甜心
So what do you think, sweetheart?
嗯  还好
Hm, it's fine.
但我觉得52街的那间更好一些
But I like the place on 52nd better.
52街  离你母亲家很近啊
52nd, that's awful close to your mother.
不不不  我们不谈我妈的事
No, no, no, we're not talking about my mother.
我倒是没关系啊
Well, I...look, it doesn't matter to me,
我喜欢住得离你妈近一些
I mean, I love being near your mother.
我很爱你母亲
I love your mother.
你何不跟我们介绍一下
So why don't you tell us
这栋大厦的情况
something about your little building?
我想你们会发现
Well, I think you'll find that
不仅我们的设施是一流的
not only are the amenities top quality,
-住户也是高素质人群  -那太好了
- so are the tenants. - That's good to hear.
是啊  因为我们不只是
Yeah, 'cause we're not just looking at
要买块地方  更是要在这儿安家的
buying square footage, but really put down some roots.
这里正是安家的明智选择
Well, that is such the right way to look at it.
是嘛
Is it?
是啊  你们还会发现
Yes, and I think you'll also find
入住的住户  他们跟你们很像
that the people who've bought here, they're like you.
年轻  上进
They're young, ambitious--
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
有什么疑问我能回答的吗
Any other questions I can answer?
对不起  我老婆  我美丽的老婆
I'm sorry. My wife here--my beautiful wife
有的时候会有点多疑  你懂吗
is just--gets a little paranoid sometimes, you know?
你都不会相信  我花了多长时间
You wouldn't believe how long it took her
才让她答应跟我约会
to just go out with me in the first place.
一生那么长
Forever.
还有其他在这儿住了一段时间的住户吗
Are there any other tenants who've been here for a while,
有没有住户  能带我们了解一下
you know, who might be able to show us
住在这里要注意的事  认识一下邻居
the ins and outs of the place, the neighborhood?
大楼两年前翻修过
Well, the building was totally renovated two years ago,
所以我们大部分的住户都是搬来不久的
So most of our tenants are newer.
我们一月份才重新开放的
We only reopened in January.
但我觉得会有些
But I think there are
老住户在这儿直接租了新居
some of the old tenants who bought in.
你说我们能跟他们谈谈吗
You think that we might be able to speak to them?
-就是想确认一下  -会让我们
- Just to be sure. - It would really make us
心里舒坦点
feel more comfortable.
她精力特充沛
She's feisty.
-我们可相爱了  -那是  那是
- So in love, so in love. - Yes, we are.
你来找我  是因为你想找个
You came to me because you wanted someone
认为你不会说谎的人帮你
who knows you always tell the truth.
-可你说谎了  -你在说什么啊
- Well, you don't. - What're you talking about?
丽萨的事
Lisa.
我那时问你  我们分开前
I asked you back then if anything had started
你们是不是就有一腿了
before we were separated.
你说没有  我也相信你了
You said it hadn't and I believed you.
那是因为我不想伤害你
'Cause I didn't wanna hurt you.
你想知道什么伤到我了吗
You wanna know what hurts me?
我原以为是我的事业心导致了我们离婚
I thought it was my ambition that caused our divorce.
-我从没这么说过  -是没有
- I never said that. - No.
但你让我以为是这样
But you let me believe it.
我本不该在那时与Lisa有染
I shouldn't have started with Lisa when I did,
可早在那之前
but it happened long after
你我就都清楚  我们的感情难以维系了
you and I both know we weren't working.
我很抱歉
Now I'm sorry.
抱歉我当时没有勇气说真话
Sorry I didn't have the courage to tell you then.
-那现在呢  -现在怎么了
- What about now? - Now?
那些人是在歪曲事实
They're manipulating the facts.
我不会为了  在我快一无所有之时
And I'm not going to apologize just because we happened
突然时来运转  而道歉
to hit it big when I was about to lose everything.
不论怎样我都会为你辩护的
I'm gonna defend you either way
因为我接了你的案子  这是我的工作
because I took this case, and that's what I do.
但如果我要堵上我的名声
But if I'm gonna stake my reputation on this,
我就要知道还有没有别的谎言
then I need to know if there are any other lies
会冒出来背后捅我一刀
that are gonna come up and sandbag me.
我现在就要知道
And I need to know right now.
谢谢
Thanks.
看来我们有很多话要聊了
I see I have some catching up to do.
人都是年少无知啊
People are stupid when they're young.
-你知道为什么吗  -我想知道
- Do you wanna know why? - I wanna know why
为什么他们在余下的生命里也那么无知
they're stupid all the other years of their lives.
格兰菲迪  不错啊
Glenfiddich. Smooth.
真不错
That's nice.
你从没结过婚
You never got married.
现在我们要分享私生活了吗
Now we're sharing our personal lives?
"直到死亡将我们分开"
"Till death do us part."
我还真信了
I actually believed it.
他在临床试验上造假了吗
Did he falsify the clinical trials?
他说他不会那么做的
He says he wouldn't do that.
那我们干嘛喝闷酒
So why are we drinking?
他说他不会那么做的
He says he wouldn't do that...
因为他本人也需要这药见效
because he needs the drug to work.
他要死了
He's dying.
奎汀也有肌萎缩侧索硬化症
Quentin has A.L.S.
帕克小姐  你为桑兹先生工作多久了
Miss parker, how long have you worked for Mr. Sainz?
实际上我是独立顾问
Well, technically, I'm an independent consultant.
但我从艾米林克斯研发之初就在这儿工作了
But I've been a part of Amylinx from the beginning.
是啊  我想你也是
Yes, I imagine you have been.
我们要确立你的可信程度
We're just trying to establish your credentials
好为他作证
for testifying for him.
你知道奎汀有肌萎缩侧索硬化症多久了
How long have you known Quentin had A.L.S.?
-一开始就知道  -那你知道
- From the beginning. - And how long have you known
他为了自救在实验结果上造假
Quentin falsified trial results to get the drug on the market,
-好让药早点上市多久了  -你说什么
- to save his own life? - What?
他才不会那么做呢
No, he wouldn't do that.
少来了丽萨  我们是一边的
Come on, Lisa, we're all on the same team here.
我们在想办法保护你爱的男人
We're trying to figure out how to protect the man you love.
我以为你相信他呢
Well, I thought you believed in him.
奎汀跟我还是夫妻的时候
You slept with Quentin
你就跟他上床了
while he was married to me.
他之前说没有这回事  我也信了
He said it never happened, and I believed him.
但现在我知道他会撒谎
But I have learned that he can lie.
所以我现在还相信他吗  不了
So do I believe in him now? No.
现在是在控制损失
This is damage control.
我们在努力保护他
We're just trying to protect him.
因为他们会查出来  他会被抓起来
Because they will find out, and he will get caught,
如果你不跟我们说实话
And if you don't tell us the real facts,
我们没法减缓他撒谎带来的损失
we can't mitigate the damage from his lie.
但他没撒谎
But he didn't lie.
我发誓
I swear.
-他没有  -但你撒谎了  是不是
- He didn't. - But you did, didn't you?
他当时病了
He was sick,
他需要那药
he needed the drug,
你为了得到药物管理局的批准不惜代价
And you would've done anything for FDA approval.
说吧  丽萨  帮我们帮他
Come on, Lisa, help us help him.
你没看到他当时的样子
You didn't see what he was like.
他都  不像他自己了
He was... barely Quentin then.
之后他有所好转
And then he got better.
我从没见过那样的事
And I've never seen anything like it.
是我发现了那件事
I was the one to see it.
到底发现了什么
See what, exactly?
六个月的实验  一百人里有一个
6 months in, 1 person out of the 100
开始出现肝功衰竭
started showing signs of liver damage.
而这会危及到获批的事
And that would jeopardize approval.
没错  我不能冒这个险
Yeah, and I couldn't take that chance,
所以我把那人请出研究了
so I took the person out of the study.
你没跟奎汀说过吗
You never told Quentin?
没  说了他会再等下去的  可我们没时间了
No, he would've waited, and we didn't have the time.
他没时间等了
He didn't have the time.
而我爱他
And I love him.
我还能怎么做
So what else could I do?
这个真相倒有一点优势
Look, there is an upside to all of this.
什么优势
Upside?
我在不知情的情况下  欺瞒了药管局
To the fact that I unknowingly defrauded the FDA?
关键就是你不知情
Well, the key word is unknowingly.
丽萨是个外来的承包人
Lisa's an outside contractor.
公司对实际造成的伤害要负责
The company may be liable for actual damages,
但我们可以把诈骗的罪名  转嫁到丽萨身上
but we can shift the blame for the fraud to Lisa.
会赔点小钱
There'd be a small payment,
但或许能让你的药留在市场上
but you might be able to keep the drug on the market.
就让丽萨当炮灰了吗
And throw Lisa under the bus?
是她先陷你于不利境地的
She was throwing you under the bus.
她是想救我的命
She was trying to save my life.
她会被刑事起诉吗
Would there be criminal charges?
有可能  她该自己请律师
Possibly. She should get her own lawyer.
我们之间利益有冲突
It's a conflict for us.
我们的目标是保护你
Look, our goal is to protect you.
我不确定
Sh...I don't know.
还有一个选择
There is an alternative.
你可以加入彻奇的诉讼
You can join Church's lawsuit.
杰西卡  我们是这公司的律师
Jessica, we're lawyers for the company.
我们不能建议他这么做
We can't advise him to do that.
-哈维  这是他的人生  -那不是重点
- Harvey, this is his life. - That's not the point.
这是我的案子  我说了算
This is my case, my call.
等等  那将意味着什么
Wait, wait, wait. What would that mean?
桑兹药厂将倒闭
Sainz pharmaceuticals would go down,
但你能分到调解费的一部分
but you'd share in the settlement.
你能再开个新公司
You could open a new company,
用另一个公司的名义继续卖你的药
keep the drug alive under a different corporate umbrella.
我不会假装跟他们一样是受害者
I'm not pretending I'm one of them.
你就跟他们一样
You are one of them.
我不能那么做  我不是那种人
Look, I can't do that. It's not who I am.
还有没有别的办法
Now isn't there another way?
你确实跟他们同病相怜
You are one of them.
他们也跟你同病相怜
And they're one of you.
迈克  我们有活要干  你在哪
Mike, we got work to do, where are you?
我现在看到你在第三会议室里呢
Oh, I'm looking at you right now in conference room C.
抱歉  我要失陪一下
I'm sorry, can you please excuse me?
在办公室里开戒酒互助会吗
AA meeting? Here in the office?
真好笑  不是  是我的诉讼
Funny. No, it's my lawsuit.
-什么诉讼  -跟强尼・卡里斯基打的那个
- Which suit is that? - Against Johnny Karinski.
弗兰克住的那栋楼
Between Frank's building
还有我跟瑞秋打算租下的那栋
and the one Rachel and I are about to buy into.
对了  我们结婚了
Oh, yeah. We're married.
说来话长
It's a long story.
你说让我大胆设想的  对吗
Look, you said think bigger, right?
我找到了15个前住户
I tracked down 15 former tenants
他们都愿出庭作证  他们受到各种骚扰
who are willing to testify to all manner of harassment
逼的他们不得不离开公寓
that forced them out of their apartments.
你连夜找来的吗
You did this overnight?
是啊  反正我也睡不着
Yeah, I couldn't sleep anyway.
总觉得有臭虫
Kept thinking I felt bedbugs.
如果我们把他们拉到法官面前
But I can get these people in front of a judge
说出他们的故事  那个薇薇安・塔纳卡
to tell their story, and there is no way
也没法扭转乾坤  救下卡里斯基的
that Vivien Tanaka can spin this to save Karinski's ass.
你该听听他们的故事
You should hear their stories.
很让人伤心  如果你还有良心的话
It'd break your heart. Uh, if you had a heart.
煽情是很好
Emotion is fine,
但是你最好还有冷酷无情的铁证做后盾
but you better have some cold, hard facts to back it up.
因为薇薇安・塔纳卡不是吃素的
Because Vivien Tanaka is no pushover.
但是
But...
做得不错  加油
It's good work. Keep at it.
我要去忙我该忙的了
I'm gonna go do what I gotta go do.
我们需要更多证据
We need more.
怎么才能得到更多的
How're we gonna get more?
迈克
Mike?
这是我们昨天去的大楼吗
Is this the building we were in yesterday?
不交房租就走人  是我的规矩
No rent, no apartment. That's my code.
对  前后照片对比
Yeah. Before and after.
我们得去买块地毯
We need to go carpet shopping.
我想你看见广告了
I see you found my ad.
这是在抢我的风头啊  哈维
Trying to steal my thunder, Harvey?
商学院  101条
Business school 101,
出自《商学院学到的101条》
遇到危机  要承认问题的存在
you have a crisis, you acknowledge the problem.
你们想要效仿的是泰诺药业  而非丰田汽车
You wanna be Tylenol, not Toyota.
都发生过产品召回事件
你现在承认这是个危机  为时稍晚
A little late for you to acknowledge this is a crisis.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
非常感谢各位今天能来
thank you very much for coming here today.
奎汀・桑兹刊登了这则广告
Quentin Sainz placed this ad
因为你们的诉讼让他清楚认识到
because your lawsuit made it clear
他的药物有他自己也不知道的副作用
that his drug had side effects that he didn't know about.
我们想了解此次问题遍及的范围有多广
We wanted to know how widespread this problem was.
我们之前收到了很多答复
We had an outpouring of response.
但不是来自像你们这样痛苦挣扎的患者
Not from people struggling like yourselves,
而是来自那些渴望继续服用此药的患者
but from people desperate to keep the drug available.
你们认为是我们说谎
You think we're lying.
你们来这儿是因为你们认为公司
You're here because you think this company
对你们有所隐瞒
has been hiding things from you.
你们说的没错  他们确有隐情
And you're right. They have.
但是奎汀想要全盘托出
But Quentin wants to come clean.
他想要告诉你们
He wants to show you
他真正在隐瞒的是什么
exactly what it is that he's been hiding.
我无法松开拳头  也不能握住东西
I can't really open it. I can't hold anything.
我也不知道能坚持工作多久
And I don't know how much longer I can keep working.
会好起来的  会好的
It'll get better, it will.
你知道会的
You know it will.
我想是吧
I guess.
我把自己的生命都堵上了
I bet my life on it.
本身患上肌萎缩性侧索硬化症就很不公平
It's not fair you got A.L.S. in the first place.
再因为服用我所发明的药引发副作用
And it's definitely not fair you had side effects
而我自己吃了却没事  也绝对不公平
from the drug I created and I didn't.
但是现在我知道副作用的存在
But now that I know they exist,
我想要完善它
I wanna fix them.
这样  像你们一样的人
So that people like you...
也许甚至于你们  都能像我现在一样健康
And maybe even you, can have what I have right now.
但是他办不到
But he can't.
如果他满足你们的索赔  他就办不到了
He can't if he gives you what you're asking.
我们不是说你们不配得到赔偿
We're not saying that you don't deserve compensation.
我们的承诺是这样的
Our commitment to you is this.
我们将提供给各位  公司的部分所有权
We are offering you partial ownership in his company.
一个正在试图拯救生命的公司
A company that is trying to save lives.
钱不会延续你们的生命
Money isn't going to help you live longer.
接受这条件吧  让奎汀
Taking the deal, and letting Quentin
努力去解决问题
try and fix the problem could.
不管你们乐不乐意
Like it or not...
你们都是一条船上的
You're all in the same boat.
给奎汀一次机会
Give Quentin the opportunity
保住这条船  别让它沉了
to keep that boat from sinking.
他们真的接受了条件
They really took the offer.
彻奇不喜欢这个结果
Church didn't like it.
但他们也不喜欢彻奇
But they didn't like church.
他们喜欢你
They liked you,
和我
and me.
谁不喜欢你呢
Who wouldn't?
你妈从来都不喜欢我
Your mother was never a fan.
你想要听真话吗
You wanna know the truth,
我父亲也不太喜欢
my father wasn't much of a fan either.
这句就是谎话了  我知道
Now that is a lie and I know it.
真话是
The real truth is,
他们从一开始就认为你比丽萨要好
they'd both take you over Lisa in a minute.
对不起
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
从此以后  绝无谎言
From now on... back to no more lies.
如果要这么说定的话
Well, if we're gonna do that...
你记得那次你的捷豹停在门外
You remember that time that your jag got sideswiped
被刮蹭的事吗
when it was parked outside the house?
记得
Yeah.
其实事实并非如此
Yeah, it didn't exactly go down that way.
当时我太生气了
I was mad.
你生气了
You were mad?
你买的午饭太难吃了  我们本可以一起吃的
Oh, you brought a sack lunch. We would've shared.
真好笑
Amusing.
这也是  你的小诉讼案
As was this, your little lawsuit.
带上你的垃圾礼物赶快逃吧  孩子
Take your sack of presents and run, kid.
你这是在自找麻烦
You're in way over your head.
我认为他会没事的
Oh, I think he'll be just fine.
-你好啊  薇薇安  -你好
- Hello, Vivien. - Hello.
菜鸟找来了行家
So the rookie called in the veteran.
不  我就是来围观的
No, no, I'm just here to watch.
我就喜欢有观众的比赛
I love spectator sports.
你喜欢观战洋基队击败小小弱旅吗
You enjoy watching the Yankees destroy a little league team?
美国联盟东区的棒球队伍之一
大卫和巨人的故事恰好是
David and Goliath happens to be
我的最爱之一
one of my favorite stories.
出自《圣经》, 牧羊人大卫杀死了强大的巨人
好吧  随你的愿  包里是什么
Okay, I'll bite. What's in the bag?
你在干什么
What're you doing?
你认出这张地毯了吗
Oh, do you recognize this carpet?
让他把那玩意弄出去
Make him get that out of here.
这是您的地毯  卡里斯基先生
This is your own carpet, Mr. Karinski.
这是从弗兰克・卡维罗的公寓里拿来的
It's from Frank Carvello's apartment.
来  感受下这纤维  这纹理
Come on. Feel the fibers, the texture,
就跟活的一样
it's almost alive.
你把臭虫都带来了
You brought bedbugs in here.
这是破坏公物  侵犯人身罪
That's vandalism, assault.
我很高兴你这么说
You know, I'm happy that you put it that way,
因为那正是我们将要起诉你委托人的罪名
because that's what we're gonna be charging your client with.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
他不是没能抵住臭虫袭击
He didn't just fail to eradicate a bedbug infestation,
他是臭虫制造者
he actually created one.
他从某幢旧楼中拽出一块地毯
Yeah, he pulled the carpet from one of his old buildings--
一块已遍布臭虫的地毯
carpet that was already infested--
然后他将它重新放回我委托人的公寓
and then he reinstalled it in my client's apartment
迫使其离开
to drive him out.
太胡扯了
That's crazy.
你也许该提醒你的委托人别作伪证
You might wanna warn your client about perjury.
房屋的入住情况  可是宣过誓的
We've got sworn testimony from the installer.
还有一张他的旧楼翻新前
And a picture of the same carpet
同样的那块地毯的照片
from one of his old buildings before it was renovated.
顺便说一句  我太太和我真的很喜欢
By the way, my wife and I really love
你改造后房屋的样子
what you've done with the place.
所以  我们要指控的罪名有
So it looks like we're talking about, what?
侵犯人身罪  违反租赁法规
Assault, violations of rental codes,
卫生管理条例
health codes,
就是些维持得体生活的基本条例啊
and you know, just basic codes of human decency.
如果纽约的陪审团听到那些
And if a jury in New York heard all that,
想想后果吧
wow, imagine the damages.
哈维  观而不语
Harvey... Spectate, please.
赶紧把那个毯子拿出去
Just get that carpet out of here.
那么  薇薇安
So, Vivien...
我第一次做得怎么样
How am I doing for my first time?
这还算是我的第一次  对吗
This still counts as my first time, doesn't it?
现在  我们不如谈谈你得赔多少钱吧
Now let's talk about how much this is going to cost you.
干吗
Yes?
觉得你会想知道
Just thought you'd like to know,
你的案件  无偿服务的那个  我赢了
your case, the pro bono... I won.
真为你高兴
How exciting for you.
但正如我所说  这只是无偿案件
But like I said, it's just a pro bono case,
对你的职业生涯并无帮助
it's not gonna help your career.
我还签下了15个新客户
I did also manage to sign 15 new clients
都想为同样的问题起诉
who are all suing for the same harassment,
而他们都会付钱
And they will be paying.
所以你可以将这个数字
So you can multiply this number...
乘以15
Times 15.
对于菜鸟来说做得不错了吧
That's not bad for rookie league.
拜托
Come on.
牺牲午餐时间值了吧
Tell me that wasn't worth missing your lunch hour for.
做你老婆真是太让我自豪了
It makes me proud to be your wife.
等等  这话从何说起
Yeah, wait, what is that coming up?
今天是我们三周年还是四周年结婚纪念吗
Is that our third, or our fourth anniversary?
五周年  你不觉得很重要吗
It's our fifth. Doesn't it mean anything to you?
当然觉得  实际上  我认为
Yeah. In fact, I think that
我们应该来个约会之夜以示庆祝
we should have a date night to celebrate.
你真搞笑
You're funny.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我不能和同事约会
I can't date anyone from the office.